<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="layout.xsl" type="text/xsl" ?>

<content>

<img style="padding: 0 10px; float: right;" src="../images/mint.png"/>

<h1>cp-m</h1>

<p style="color: red"> IMPORTANT cp-m is still in early stages of development. Becuase of this
the following documentation might not refect the actualy state of functionailty.</p>

<h2>Managed Copy</h2>

<p>cp-m is a managed copy tool. It much like the standard cp command with the interacive
-i option set, but goes even further, by allowing the end user to see diffs and to 
commit or abort the entire copy procedure before actually making and writes to disk.</p>

<h2>Basic Usage</h2>

<p>Using <code>cp-m</code> is super easy. Here is the most basic example:</p>

  <pre>
    $ cp-m FROM.txt TO.txt
  </pre>

<p>This simply copies FROM.txt file to TO.txt. Just like using <code>cp</code>.
Of course we assume FROM.txt already exits, and TO.txt does not. If FROM.txt
doesn't exit it will report an error, as expected. But if TO.txt already exits?</p>

  <pre>
    $ cp-m FROM.txt TO.txt
    KEY (d)iff (c)opy (s)kip (a)ll (q)uit?
      exits: TO.txt ?
  </pre>

<p>Now we have a choice. We can examine the difference between what the current file
looks like and what it will become, or we can choose to go ahead and copy the file,
overwriting the current file, or we can skip it and not copy it after all.</p>

<p>The last two options only mater if you're copying more that one file at a time,
in which case 'all' allows you to skip all remaining files that already exist,
and 'quit' allows you to abort any copying altogether. There is an option to copy all
remaining files irregardless, but we only get thet by passing the --force option to
to the <code>cp-m</code> command. This is an added precaution. We don't want to delete
important files on accident!</p>

<p>Finally, after we have made out choice we we be asked if we wish to commit out
selections.</p>

  <pre>
    $ cp-m FROM.txt TO.txt
    KEY (d)iff (c)opy (s)kip (a)ll (q)uit?
      exits: TO.txt ?
    Commit (y/N)? 
  </pre>

<p>Only by entering 'y' here is the copy made.</p>

<br/>

</content>

